When a product team receives pull
requests from some central team, they
view it kind of like unwelcome advice
coming from an in-law. Most people that
start thinking about large scale change,
the most natural thing for us to think
of as developers as pull requests or
mass pull requests. Does this then start
creating pull requests in every single
project and then who then goes about
merging all of those pull requests in
more in unison? I think we've identified
over the years the room for something we
call pullbased change and room for
something like you actually use the
right word pushbased change. They're
just looking for a reason to reject it.
And so we really focus a lot on how do
we put the problem in front of a
developer in the kind of IDP sort of way
like here's where you're at relative to
an objective but it's meant to be
informative and here's the button at a
moment in time of your convenience. This
rescue is ready for you and we got you
99% of the way there 95% of the way
there. whatever the case might be, do
it. And so what you'll see is individual
product teams doing pull requests to
their subset of the business. And that
has a much higher acceptance rate than
centrally issued mass pure.
[Music]
Hello and welcome to another episode of
the AI native dev. And joining me today
is Jonathan Schneider who is the CEO and
co-founder of Madern and Madern um is a
company that is really focused around
the analysis of code and also the
refactoring of code bases. So welcome
Jonathan. How are you
>> doing? Well, thank you Simon. Glad glad
to be here.
>> Oh absolutely pleasure to have you. And
whereabouts are you whereabouts are you
calling in from today Jonathan? I'm in
lovely Miami which is was one of the
best moves I made a few years ago coming
from the west coast to Miami.
>> Oh wow. Over on the San Francisco Bay
area style.
>> The company was actually founded in
Seattle which itself is an interesting
accidental story but you know founded in
2020. The first person we hired was in
Seattle. So I just up and moved to
Seattle and we worked in
>> parks on a bench for the first little
while. Um but after a couple years kind
of moved uh over here to Miami where
it's uh it's much better for time zone
and weather as you can imagine.
>> Oh absolutely. Yeah. The connection to
the to to to Europe and other places I
think from a time zone perspective very
much more convenient and I relate very
much to the to the Seattle weather being
being in the UK
>> of course.
Um so yeah I kind of mentioned Madern
you know it deals with the problems that
developers have about refactoring about
rewriting existing code and tell us a
little bit about from the from the from
you know your point of view what was the
reason you created Maderna what were the
biggest problems that you were trying to
solve at the time and how old is Maderna
as well
>> the company itself is nearing five years
now but the technology open rewrite that
goes behind it actually goes back almost
10 I was working for Netflix engineering
tools and in some ways somewhat
responsible for shephering the
organization through large scale changes
at the time like Java 6 to7 and trying
to get off into logging library and and
these sort of things and while you know
I spent a lot of effort and a lot of my
team spent effort on trying to provide
things like early internal developer
portals like basically dashboards to
show people where they are relative to
where we want them to be. We found that
it resulted in approximately
no action towards the objective. And so
just interviewing those teams, those
product teams, and saying, "What would
it take for me to move you from one
thing to another?" They would say,
"Well, you know, do it for me.
Otherwise, I got something else to do,
right? I've got," and it's true, they
had a ton of feature pressure on them.
So these kinds of efforts were always
back back burner, right? not not top of
mind if they weren't required. So
>> uh so the framework started then to try
to literally do it for them you know try
to provide ways of automating this
change. I had gone on to the spring
team, founded a project called
micrometer. So completely unrelated uh
started working on a product called
Spker which also open source out of
Netflix um for advanced continuous
delivery and our co-founder Olga
Gakunich and I were working with a lot
of the large banks and retailers and so
forth trying to build advanced
continuous delivery concepts and uh you
know they'd say talk to me in a year
when I'm done moving spring boot one to
two or this to that you know and and so
it it's just kind of like we got pulled
into this by seeing how repeatable and
ubiquitous this problem really was.
>> Yeah. And and the value in terms of the
value of people, you know, doing a lot
of the rewrites and I guess things like
that. Um what would you when you're
talking to developers and developers
like, you know, I've got a ton of things
that I need to get need to get done.
What would you provide them as like this
is the reason why this is important and
why you should, you know, consider this
high on your list of of things to deal
with? I think luckily it already is high
on the list and we hear in various
different ways. Um this is roughly 30
for to 40% of just total engineering
time. It's just
>> keeping the lights on. You're using an
open source third party thing. It makes
a change to it API like you have to
continually restitch the application or
it ceases to function. So it's just a
reality of software development and the
more net new code that we write the
harder that problem becomes.
>> Yeah. Really?
>> Yeah. And it's one of those things that
I guess it's considered almost like
technical debt. Some people kind of want
new features from a framework which is
only available in a new new version. But
it's just general good hygiene, good
software hygiene to to maybe not
bleeding bleeding edge but very often
stay high up the you know nearer the uh
the the latest. Uh,
>> one of the more, you know, evolved ways
of thinking about this because you
mentioned technical debt actually comes
from shelter insurance, you know, kind
of a midsize property and casualty
insurer in the Midwest US. They they
actually tag technical debt on their
backlog differently from maintenance.
And I think that's a really subtle
distinction where, you know, we used to
think of technical debt as something
where I took a shortcut and I'm going to
have to pay that down later. But it's
really, you know, I chose to do that and
I I really identify with the developer
position right now, which is that I
could make all the best architectural
choices, the best language choices, the
best library choices. I could be
absolutely perfect right now, today on
July 15th, and you know, six months from
now, that thing has shifted. So it's it
is really more like maintenance that you
have to do on a car or a house. Uh if
you don't do it, you can't expect the
thing to continue to function.
>> Yeah. No, absolutely. in the era of AI,
I guess I guess there's a number of
tools that um with pure LLM
um can kind of like do some of this um
they can understand and and and somewhat
analyze um code bases. They can make
changes. They can they can do a number
of things that even somewhat reasonable
at completely changing language from one
to the other. What would you say what
would you say I guess from the from the
pure AI point of view are the the
advantages and maybe some of the things
that they're not so good at when
thinking about uh any kind of uh
maintenance or framework changes keeping
up to date that kind of that kind of
thing. Yeah, I think broadly I would
consider AI based or pure AI based
solutions to be concentrated around
authorship experiences. And by
authorship I mean I've got one
repository open in the IDE or I'm you
know I've got a CLI based tool like a
cloud code pointed at a particular
repository and I'm asking to do a thing
and that thing might be a feature
development. It could be it could of
course be like you say language to
language whatever the case might be. Um
but there's going to be you know there's
going to be a degree of time it spends
on that one repository. Mhm.
>> Mainten maintenance type activities or
you know modernization type activities
tend to be crosscutting
and at most I'd say you know even
midsize customers of ours we're dealing
with hundreds thousands sometimes tens
of thousands of repositories.
So that that workflow of like you know
uh CD to a directory say claude ask it
to do something commit clone the next
one CD into that directory claude commit
uh just doesn't really scale to the
problem. Yeah, because I guess if if you
have an enterprise scale app and you
want to make a change to a framework or
something like that, you probably have a
vast number of files that need to be
that need to be adapted. How good would
you say
um AI tools in general
um would be at increasing their context
windows to be able to take in a number
of you know more projects, more files?
Is the is the limit then the the context
window itself? uh does the LLM you find
get a little bit more confused the more
context you throw at it or is it kind of
just the experience of well how do I
even pass all of this if this is spread
across hundreds or thousands of repos
what would you say are the the limiting
factors
>> right yeah first of all you know
increasing context window does come with
a trade-off and that's that there's this
inverse relationship between context
window and the attention mechanism
that's fundamental to LM so
>> you would expect, you know, as context
window increases for there to be more
confusion, more just less focus just as,
you know, I hate to enter
anthropomorphize these things, but the
same for us. You know, you throw a book
at somebody, say, "Read the whole book
and I'm going to quiz you on it." You're
going to have a lot less, you know,
targeted, uh, feedback on that than if I
ask you a question about a very specific
part. Mh.
>> So, um, that's that's a fundamental
trade-off I don't think is is really
going away. Um, the other thing is that,
you know, even when it's focused on a
narrow uh, you know, narrow part of the
code, there's it's still ultimately a
probabilistic system. So, while the
changes can be fantastic, I use these
things like crazy. If you need to apply
the same change across again thousands
or tens of thousands of reposttors, you
really don't want to scale the human
review of those changes to the number of
changes that are being made. Mhm.
>> So at the end what you really want is
the actor to be deterministic
but building that machine or that cookie
cutter that you can then go use to stamp
out you know low variability cookies
across the codebase itself can be uh
developed with with the assistance of an
LLM.
>> Yeah. Interesting. So where would you
say the kind of solution lives then? Do
you think you know is is it completely
nonLM? Is it somewhat between NLM and
and and more traditional development?
>> It's really it's really a mixture. So
what you know I started working on 10
years ago with open rewrite was really a
a refactoring uh engine and it's a it's
a program. So it has a deterministic
output every time it's you know has a
unit testing framework to it and so
forth to you know to basically cover all
the variations that are inherent in
code. Uh but it used to be that you
would encounter a problem like say I'm
trying to move from one framework
version to another and um
the uh I have to write out all these
recipes.
>> So for something like a Spring Boot 3
migration for example, Spring Boot 3
migration, there's uh almost 3,400
recipes in the catalog right now to just
deal with that migration.
>> And and tell us what a what a recipe is.
Maybe we go a little bit deeper in into
open rewrite now. What's a what's the
function of a recipe?
>> So a recipe is a program that makes a
particular code change. That could be a
dependency change, it could be a
property change, it could be, you know,
this API changed from this to that, you
know, and so if you imagine just kind of
looking through the release notes of a
change uh or an upgrade, each of the
steps that's in that migration guide
would be itself a distinct recipe that's
operating in the larger composite recipe
to accomplish that thing.
>> Gotcha. Okay. So, so if there's I guess
there's a couple of steps there. If you
if you feel like you're going from
version X to version X+1, you need to
first of all identify what are the
recipes that are that you need to think
about and are those instances of that
code that you're actually making changes
to, you know, does that trigger certain
recipes that you actually need to
perform an action? I presume.
>> That's right. That's right. And so it so
you know the the historically for us
it's been we have thousands of open
source recipes. Uh you know if the
problem statement that you have happens
to fit well to the catalog that we have
great you can kind of ready to go get
value right now. If there's some custom
change you want to make um that's that's
going to involve writing new recipes.
And so, um, the perceived cost of
writing new recipes used to be, well, I
have to learn how to write the f, you
know, with the framework and I have to,
you know, um, you know, I just have to
spend time doing it. And whether it was
worth writing recipes or not, um, was
there was like a diminishing return to
it. It really depended on how many
changes that you had to make and was it
60, was it 60,000, you know, and is it
worth it or not? And what I'm seeing I
think with with LMS right now is that
the cost to write net new custom recipes
is approaching zero. So as one example
just a few days ago I was talking with a
banking engineering executive that
actually literally described this
problem to me. They you know they said
I'm trying to move from on-pre
infrastructure to containerbased
infrastructure. Key problem is right now
a lot of these applications are writing
files to log or logs to files. instead
they have to be written to sis out
because we have a Splunk agent that's
connected to these containers and so
that will scoop up SIS out and send it
on to Splunk. I literally just kind of
transcribed what he was saying in just a
paragraph and said, "Go plan the
recipes. Go write them." And in the back
of my mind, I thought, well, I know, you
know, I've been around software long
enough. I know that this is just going
to be a lot of logging configuration
changes. Like you're going to have to
change a logback configuration, got
change log forj configuration, but what
are all the variations of this that I'm
going to have to accommodate? Um, and
sure enough, like a a cloud code would
just go out and make a plan of six or 10
or 15 steps and just start knocking out
the recipes.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, because open rewrite has a very
declarative framework, it's like, you
know, you assert before after text in
the code, it's hard for the model to
cheat at the test. You know, it just
writes this test before after
>> and then it works hard to make that test
pass because the test itself is somewhat
inflexible. So it's interesting that you
know the the as we think about like
writing frameworks like this the more
declarative we make our our tests um the
better the outcome is in the in the main
source code. So would you would you have
the LLM
uh write the tests as well as run them
as well or how? So the LLM came up with
six or 10 steps whatever the case might
be and its first move then is going to
say this is what log back configuration
looks like before and after and this is
log forj configuration before and after
and so it writes out all the tests and
then it starts working on the main
source code of the recipes
um you know working until those tests
pass essentially. So it was about 20
minutes from me transcribing this
message um to I had the first six
functional recipes
um we deployed that to that tenant and
ran it on nearly 10,000 repositories and
here's all the applications that would
have to change and how many of them use
this versus that and you know then you
can kind of now it's now it becomes a a
feedback cycle of do I like the change
is there anything missing is you know,
and you and you just feed that back into
the LM. I didn't like this change. Go
change this. I didn't like this change.
Go change this. And it iterates on the
recipe further. It's interesting because
I guess there are there are going to be
very often some some minor specifics
where actually you might want to do
something slightly different. Is that a
manual review or is there are there ways
in which you know you've used other
technology to to to more be a judge for
those kind of reviews? It depends on the
type of change. So for us and this is
going to sound strange but we have a
recipe actually an open rewrite recipe
that itself is something we call
compilation verification which we uh
will run some other set of recipes and
then we'll just verify that the compiler
would pass on that file after the
change. Uh that's actually doesn't
require the whole build to run. So
there's some special sauce to how that
particular recipe works, but that itself
is a judge. So you know, I can basically
work through the release notes making
all the changes and see at the end
whether I've missed something or I've
just done something wrong. And then that
becomes this kind of cycle that the LM
can feed off of itself. Mhm.
>> There's of course going to be a lot of
changes, especially configuration type
changes that are not verifiable with
just compilation or even running unit
tests in many cases.
>> Absolutely. In my mind, I'm thinking
this sounds great, but then once you do
this across scale, across a ton of um
different repositories and projects,
um does this does this then start
creating pull requests in every single
project? And then, you know, who who
then goes about merging all of those
pull requests in more in unison than
than than anything? What's the logistics
I guess of actually then pushing this
into into more of a production build?
>> This is such a great question and and
indeed I think most people that start
thinking about large scale change the
most natural thing for us to think of as
developers is pull requests or mass pull
requests. Mhm.
>> Um we I think we've identified over the
years the
room for something we call pollbased
change and room for something like you
actually use the right word pushbased
change like this.
In general my observation about the
social dynamics of mass pull requests is
that when a product team receives pull
requests from some central team they
view it kind of like unwelcome advice
coming from an in-law. They're just
looking for a reason to reject it. I
mean, you could imagine you're at that
like
>> holiday table and your, you know,
>> mother-in-law is like, "Oh, you got too
many pounds on you right now. I think
you could do something about that."
You're going to be like, "Hey, you know,
I'm busy." You know, like it's, you
know, I'm getting older. You know,
you're trying to you're trying to make
excuses. You're trying to uh However,
you know, if you look at yourself in the
mirror and you think, you know, it's
time ready to start, you know, hitting
the gym, you're just I just more
naturally likely to take that advice.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And so we really focus a lot
on how do we put the problem in front of
a developer in the kind of IDP sort of
way like here's where you're at relative
to an objective but it's you know it's
it's meant to be informative and here's
the button
>> at a moment in time of your convenience
this recipe is ready for you and we got
you 99% of the way there 95% of the way
there whatever the case might be do it.
Um, and so you what you'll see is
individual product teams doing pull
requests to their subset of the business
and that has a much higher acceptance
rate than a centrally issued mass pure
>> and and when the pull requests are
created is there typically no work that
needs to be done or or will is there a
kind of like a um you know a certain
weight that comes with every single pull
request whereby development teams will
need to at the minimum I guess do some
kind of review but also maybe make
changes. what what's the what's the
what's the fixed cost? I guess
>> it very much depends on the change. So
something like a log for shell event um
is is you know what this vulnerability
high high impact you know we need to get
it done now short timetable that's
actually something that's good for
pushbased change that's going to be top
down driven somebody mass issues PRs to
everyone there's somebody kind of like
with a clipboard making sure everybody's
done but the really the review of that
is pretty pretty simple um it's going to
make the same kind of change everywhere
once you see one of them, you just kind
of mass commit them. You don't look at
every individual change. Uh so that's
that's one of those things that that
gets through quickly. We have other
kinds of changes like I think about
dependency vulnerability repair um and
bumping both direct and transitive
dependencies
>> whose vulnerability fixes are only a
patch version away from the minor
release I'm already on. Those are things
let's just push through, right? And you
know almost automate the push through of
that. However, if the fix is a minor
version away from the patch or the minor
I'm already on h you know now it's a
little more situational like you know
Jackson makes minor release changes that
the app may not be functional.
>> So you've actually got the same recipe
running in two different configurations.
One of which is fully automated and one
of which is maybe a little less
frequent. Maybe we do it once a week and
requires a little bit of human review.
>> Yeah.
>> And that's and so that's okay. you know
that's we we just do that a little bit
differently.
>> Yeah. It was funny actually cuz when you
when you were talking about the
capabilities there my mind immediately
did think security security issues you
know a developer gets a u I mean my
background in sneak of course whereby
you know developers are told there's a
vulnerability at this level and this
transitive maybe this is the version of
the direct you need to upgrade in order
to to to to consume that fix. Um, from a
developer's point of view, it's almost
distraction. And the more you can do to
ease that that ability to say, look, to
get security off your back or to get to,
you know, eliminate this backlog of
issues, we've come 99% of the way to to
to fixing this for you with a level of
confidence that, you know, you can you
can feel good that this isn't going to
break anything. It's been tested and
those types of things. that that that
seems like a really super valuable super
valuable use case.
>> It's one of the pillars. Yeah. So I
think application modernization,
security vulnerability repair, those are
two key pillars and ones that we've
known about for a long time.
>> Maybe to transition to the third one and
this is the one that's a little more
surprising I think is is this large
scale impact analysis. And so when we
when we first when I first started open
rewrite it was all about making a code
change. I hadn't even imagined the you
know kind of large scale search or
impact analysis use case yet
>> and so we c we came to understand this
even I think one or two years into
Madern's existence that a recipe could
in addition to making a code change just
mark something as found
>> you know I found this thing right here
so maybe then I'm doing a search for a
particular use of a API and I'm going to
find all of those and um and I'm able to
use the richness that's in that lossless
semantic tree. It's not just the
abstract syntax tree, but it's
everything the compiler knows, all the
transitive dependencies. So, I really
can accurately identify every single use
case of a particular API.
>> And then there was one step beyond that,
which was well, it's great looking at
all the individual search results, but
I'm trying to get a holistic view
of what these use like these call sites
look like across again thousands of
repositories. So
>> at that point uh open reed a a a piece
of functionality called data tables
which is just recipes can emit a row uh
of data with uh columns according to a
schema of the recipes choosing and if
you imagine this you know recipes are
running on many different repositories
and each of them is contributing rows to
the same aggregated table then when I'm
looking for say like an API like that
the end result is a table CSV or an
Excel file or whatever which just the
the inventory of every single occurrence
of this and what repository it existed
in and what business unit it was in. And
so recipes more and more even if they
were making changes started producing
these data tables as well just because
that was useful. Mhm.
>> Then we turn the table to or turn the
turn the uh clock to you know 2024
and tool function calling comes about
with large language models and we
suddenly recognize that we have in our
possession or the community's possession
here thousands of these recipes that are
producing data tables of various sorts.
And if we improve the description text
on those recipes, we can basically bolt
all those recipes to a model as tools
and say, "Hey, when you have a question
about the code at large, not just the
code you're looking at right now, ask me
um just ask me if there's a recipe or
series of recipes that would help you
answer that question." And so a model's
able to read the recipe description and
its option descriptions and its data
tables and what they mean, select one,
run it, uh, get the output and then
aggregate that, pre-agregate that in
some way to to surface some result. This
has been the sort of uh, big sea change
I think in our uh, the last you know
eight eight or nine months at this
point.
>> That sounds that sounds really powerful.
So, so you essentially have a mapping
then between a kind of effectively an LL
an LLM tool directly to a recipe that
can exist in in a in a project or repo
uh for for the the code in that repo. So
then if I were to ask LM if I was to ask
questions of the of the code or of your
of your project, the LLM will have deep
insights into where certain things are
being used, how they can be changed uh
as as well. And you expose this is
effectively exposed via an MCP server.
Is that right?
>> That's right.
>> Yeah. So it's both. It's you know we
kind of expose a direct chat experience
to say just ask a question about the
code. Again, not just one repository
potentially. and one of our largest
customers is nearly five billion lines
of source code under management. So
that's the context we're we're dealing
with is like five billion lines of
source code. Uh you could just ask this
question but you can then also expose it
as an MCP server and the key use case
there is when I'm in a cloud code or
something like that. Say I'm I'm like I
had an example last week. I'm in a
microser. I want to add a middleware
cache to this microser. I know I use
middleware caches and a bunch of other
uh services you know and I want to use
the same sort of pattern I use
everywhere else. So when I say you know
add a middleware cache please make it
consistent with the rest of my codebase.
Well you know cloud's training set has
doesn't know what's consistent in the
rest of my codebase. Um nor does looking
at that one repository which lacks a
middleware cache now
you know it they can't infer that from
the code as it is. And so that's an
example of where claude then reaches out
to that MCP server and says go find me
all the places where you know this this
type of middleware cache is used and and
and give me the examples and so it'll
then pull examples one at a time from
different repositories and use that to
inform it how to develop that that new
code over here. Really interesting.
>> Yeah, absolutely. And from the agentive
point of view where you kind of like
have you know agents agents kind of like
asking these questions thinking about it
more and and having this available to
those agents is is it's going to it's
going to provide is going to provide you
know more valid and correct answers as
it as it as it creates.
What what about if we was to look at
more kind of like open source? So
obviously there's going to be a number
of things which we'll which we'll be
consuming from open source as well as
our internal um our internal projects
and and and repos
you know is there support available for
for you know being able to analyze and
and and look at other other projects uh
in and around the open as well.
>> Yeah. So we for our customers will do
what we call mass ingestion. We'll
ingest their whole codebase in the form
of these loss of semantic tree
artifacts. And so that's that's really
the same data model that open source
open rewrite uses but serialized to
disk. And so these MCP servers and so
forth are able to operate on vast
business units rather than just kind of
like going through and parsing each one
one at a time.
>> That same thing that we're doing for
private code we've done for close to
four billion lines now of open source
code. So um we run that service just
app.mio is a kind of a free service to
anybody. um just you know it's just
available uh via GraphQL API and so
forth. So um so yes in in this case um
the uh model is able to always look at
proprietary code and open source code to
the extent that we know about it um
>> you know equivalently.
>> Yeah, sounds good. and and and going
forward, I guess, thinking thinking
further out into the distance where
whereby, you know, prompts turn into
specs and things like that, what what's
I guess your your more longer term
vision of of of how um as AI becomes
more capable, as people will be able to
uh lean more into AI, how how do you see
that working with uh with things like
open rewrite?
>> I think the key value here for us has
always been this data. There's data
about code that's you know that's not
just at the syntax tree level or the
text level but everything the compiler
knows and that's unfortunately a very
difficult problem to produce because you
you have to side inject yourself into
the compiler to get that data out and
how even to invoke the compiler for an
arbitrary uh enterprise repository is a
very layered problem I would say so um I
don't think the value of that data
essentially like data lake of deep white
code data is going to go away. Um the
kinds of ways we uh apply it are going
to continue to change and this example
here of um you know allowing say a
coding agent to look up the way code is
used elsewhere is just one new use case
I wouldn't have imagined a year or two
ago. Mhm.
>> Uh but um as for spec driven development
right now, I think um that day feels
like it's it's here, right? It's already
it's already a reality. It's it's
definitely how I use coding agents. I
always ask them to write out a plan um
to make that plan to reify it on disk so
it's not just in its memory.
>> Um to continue to edit that plan as it
moves along. Um and uh you know more
recently I've started to think well sure
put the plan on disk but when I'm doing
something new and something cool I have
it write the plan to disk
I sub get subm module clone our
documentation into that repository and I
say if there's room to update the
documentation with this go ahead and do
that too and then the last thing is to
add to have it writing a blog post as
we're working on this feature. together.
So, it's really doing three different
activities. Updating documentation,
writing that blog post that's going to
explain our work together, and also, you
know, maintaining a detailed plan about
uh about what we're going to do and what
we've done.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And it seems to me almost
like uh the the you know the code
generation still needs to happen and and
and it seems like you're injected at
that stage whereby when the LLM needs to
make decisions about what to build, what
to write, how to make changes, how to
upgrade versions and things like that,
that's where it's automatically injected
and it's in its and it's using or or
open rewrite there at the at the at the
source. Awesome. Um any any next steps
in terms of uh uh you know what's what's
next? uh what what are the biggest
challenges right now for you and what's
next?
>> For me, I think the the big
responsibility that's on our shoulders
is to expand that lake. Um so it's it's
it's always adding new languages.
Um really deeply integrating with their
tooling and their compilers and just
extracting as much density of
information as we can out of them. Um
because and so one of the really
interesting and surprising results of
the last couple years has been as we've
added new languages like JavaScript and
Python and C we discovered that the loss
of semantic tree model for those is
highly overlapping with the Java
original loss of semantic tree to the
point where we actually have them extend
the base J LST that's formed our
>> our uh Java capability to this point.
What that leads to then is that some
recipes we originally wrote for Java
automatically work on C and Python and
JavaScript in a really surprising way.
So
>> um think about a um a search recipe
called find SQL which is just looking
for string literals that have SQL in
them or binary concatenations of literal
or
>> um when we wrote that originally for
Java because JavaScript, Python and C#
extend from J and use the same J.Literal
construct that recipe actually works
there as well. So every time we add a
new language, it's like it's like
flipping on a light switch on another
corner of the world that we didn't look
at before. And um and to me that's the a
big part of our our road map is just
continue to turn the lights on more and
more places.
>> Yeah. Awesome. For people who wanted to
uh wanted to try out obviously you
mentioned open rewrite is is open source
so people can that's right people can
have a play with that and uh and modern.
>> Yeah absolutely. you know, our our site
mad.ai has uh of course references to
the open reite docs as well along with a
number of other materials and uh if you
want to go straight to open reite just
docs.openreite.org.
>> Awesome. Wonderful. Well, Jonathan, it's
been a real pleasure actually and very
insightful. Thank you for going Thank
you for going deeper with us on on on
the some of these problems. Um yeah,
feel free to uh feel free to jump to
some of those uh some of those links for
those uh for those who are listening.
And uh we really appreciate your time,
Jonathan.
>> Thank you.
>> Awesome. Thanks for listening, everyone.
And tune in to the next episode.
[Music]